A Guide to the Washington Irving Collection
University of Virginia Library
- PHOTOGRAPHS AND PRINTS
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders, Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders, (original pen and ink drawing by Jacques Reich), Port
  - Washington Irving, as an older man, head and shoulders, 1896; Engr
  - Washington Irving, as and older man, seated (by Alonzo Chappel), Engr three copies
  - Washington Irving, as an older man, head and shoulders (by S. Hollyer), Etch
  - Washington Irving, as an older man, head and shoulders (by T. Johnson), Engr facsimile
  - Washington Irving, as an older man, head and shoulders, Photo
  - Washington Irving, from portrait as older man, seated, n. d.; Photo
  - " Washington Irving and his Friends at Sunnyside" (from painting by Christian Schussele), [1863]; Photo
  - Grave of Washington Irving, n. d.; Photo
  - Sunnyside, close, n. d.; Photo
  - Sunnyside, far away, n. d.; Photo
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - The Commissioner-General of Police of Marseilles, France to the American Consul, [1804]; ALS, 2 p.
    w/ addr, re: Washington Irving's passport
  - Washington Irving to a sister, n. d.; ALS, 1 p. (fragment)
  - Charles Leslie to Washington Irving, [1817 Dec 22]; ALS, 1 p. (fragment)
  - Requests for books at the British Museum, 1819; ANS, 1 p.
  - Agreement of Washington Irving with Messrs. Galignani and Didot to edit a collection of English Literature, 1824 Mar 14; AD, 2 p.
  - Three lines in Washington Irving's hand, 1837 Aug 15; AMs, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving's autograph, 1851 Dec 10; S
  - Washington Irving's autograph, along with others, n. d.; S
  - to Washington Irving: 7 invitations, 1 envelope and 2 calling cards, Misc, 2 p.
  - List of Spanish Manuscripts [possibly for Life of Columbus ] in Washington Irving's hand, AMs, 1 p.
  - Regimental orders, 97th Regiment, 44th Brigade, N.Y.S. Infantry, signed by Ebenezer Irving, 1818 May 19; printed broadside 1 p.
  - From National Cyclopaedia of American Biography, re: Washington Irving, n. d.; printed article, 2 p.
  - Article, "Irving Relics on Exhibition", 1869 Sep 13; Pntd, 1 p.